Guide to the Department of Religious Studies, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Records, circa 1900-1988; Accession 1990-A-017
  - FINANCIAL AID, FELLOWSHIPS and ENDOWMiENTS
    - Financial Awards: Students
      - 1968-1969 (Box 11, Folder 477)
      - 1969-1970 (Box 11, Folder 478)
    - Supplementary Financial Aid Applications, 1963-1964 (Box 11, Folder 479)
  - EXAMINATIONS (GRADUATE) AND GREs
    - American Church History, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 480)
    - Christian Ethics, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 481)
    - Christian Ethics, 1960-1962 (Box 12, Folder 482)
    - Church History, undated (Box 12, Folder 483)
    - Church History, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 484)
    - Comparative Religions, undated (Box 12, Folder 485)
    - Contemporary Theology, undated (Box 12, Folder 486)
    - Early Christian Lit. and History, undated (Box 12, Folder 487)
    - Ethics Research Project, undated (Box 12, Folder 488)
    - History of Christian Doctrine, undated (Box 12, Folder 489)
    - History of Philosophy, undated (Box 12, Folder 490)
    - Judaism and Old Testament History, undated (Box 12, Folder 491)
    - New Testament Studies, 1961-1963 (Box 12, Folder 492)
    - New Testament Theology, undated (Box 12, Folder 493)
    - Old Testament History and Lit., undated (Box 12, Folder 494)
    - Philosophical Theology, undated (Box 12, Folder 495)
    - Project for Greek Exegesis and Hellenistic Greek, undated (Box 12, Folder 496)
    - Psychology of Religion- Dittes, 1961-1962 (Box 12, Folder 497)
    - Reformation, undated (Box 12, Folder 498)
    - Sociology of Religion, undated (Box 12, Folder 499)
    - Theological, Social and Philosophical Ethics, undated (Box 12, Folder 500)
    - Graduate Student Records, 1963-1970 (Box 12, Folder 501)
    - GRE Study and Handbook, 1949-1957 (Box 12, Folder 502)
    - GRE Information, 1964-1969 (Box 12, Folder 503)
    - Preliminary Examinations
      - Instructions, no date (Box 12, Folder 504)
      - Fall 1953 (Box 12, Folder 505)
      - Spring, Fall 1954 (Box 12, Folder 506)
      - Spring 1956 (Box 12, Folder 507)
      - Fall 1956 (Box 12, Folder 508)
      - Spring 1957 (Box 12, Folder 509)
      - Fall 1957 (Box 12, Folder 510)
      - 1958 May (Box 12, Folder 511)
      - 1960 May (Box 12, Folder 512)
      - 1963 Jan (Box 12, Folder 513)
      - 1963 May (Box 12, Folder 514)
      - General Examination Schedule (Box 12, Folder 515)
      - General Examination Program (Box 12, Folder 516)
    - General Examinations
      - Fall 1958 (Box 12, Folder 517)
      - 1955-1959, Dept. (Box 12, Folder 518)
      - Fall 1961 (Box 12, Folder 519)
      - Spring 1961 (Box 12, Folder 520)
      - Proposed Revision, 1961-1962 (Box 12, Folder 521)
      - 1962 May (Box 12, Folder 522)
      - 1962 Oct (Box 12, Folder 523)
      - 1905 May (Box 12, Folder 524)
      - 1963 Oct (Box 12, Folder 525)
      - 1964 Jan (Box 12, Folder 526)
      - 1964 May (Box 12, Folder 527)
      - 1964 Oct (Box 12, Folder 528 - 529)
      - 1965 Jan (Box 12, Folder 530)
      - 1965 Jan (Box 12, Folder 531)
      - 1965 May (Box 12, Folder 532)
      - 1965 Oct (Box 12, Folder 533)
      - 1966 Jan (Box 12, Folder 534)
      - 1966 May (Box 12, Folder 535)
      - 1967 Jan (Box 12, Folder 536)
      - 1967 May (Box 12, Folder 537)
      - 1967 Oct (Box 12, Folder 538)
      - 1968 Jan (Box 12, Folder 539)
      - 1968 May (Box 12, Folder 540)
      - 1968 Oct (Box 12, Folder 541)
      - 1969 Jan (Box 12, Folder 542)
      - 1969 May (Box 12, Folder 543)
      - 1969 Oct (Box 12, Folder 544)
      - 1970 Jan (Box 12, Folder 545)
      - 1970 May (Box 12, Folder 546)
      - 1971 Jan (Box 12, Folder 547)
      - 1971 May (Box 12, Folder 548)
      - 1973 Feb (Box 12, Folder 549)
      - 1973 May (Box 12, Folder 550)
      - 1973 Oct (Box 12, Folder 551)
      - American Church History, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 552)
      - Hist. Christian Doctrine, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 553)
      - Christian Social Teachings, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 555)
      - Christology, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 556)
      - Church History, 1949-1964 (Box 12, Folder 557)
      - Comparative Religion, 1956-1960 (Box 12, Folder 558)
      - Christian Ethics, 1945-1962 (Box 12, Folder 559)
      - Gen., Contemp. and Systematic Theology, 1957-1968 (Box 12, Folder 560)
      - Greek Exegesis, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 561)
      - Hebrew and Aramaic, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 562)
      - Hellenism, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 563)
      - Judaism, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 564)
      - Misc., 1958-1965 (Box 12, Folder 565)
      - New Test., Early Christian, 1954-1964 (Box 12, Folder 566)
      - Old Test. Literature and History, 1959-1963 (Box 12, Folder 567)
      - Hist. of Philosophy, Philosophical Theology, 1958-1959 (Box 12, Folder 568)
      - Hist. of Philosophy, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 569 - 570)
      - Hist. of Philosophy, 1965 January (Box 12, Folder 571)
      - Soc. of Religion, 1955-1965 (Box 12, Folder 572)
      - Systematic Theology, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 573)
  - GENERAL EXAMINATIONS, INDIVIDUAL
    - Peterson, undated (Box 13, Folder 599 - 600)
    - Miscellaneous, 1959-1960 (Box 13, Folder 604)
    - Sample Exams (originals), 1967 (Box 13, Folder 605)
    - Language Exams, ETS: Correspondence, Forms, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 606)
    - Language Exams: French, 1964-1970 (Box 13, Folder 607)
    - Language Exams: German, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 608)
- Faculty records, 1968-2006; Accession 2008-A-143
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2082
- Department of Religious Studies records, 1992-2002; Accession 2009-A-202
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2038
  - Audit, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Admissions summary, 1995-2003 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Buddhism study, 1992-2002 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Teaching fellowship prize, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Records of Wayne Meeks, Chairman of the Religious Studies Department, 1972-2003; Accession 2016-A-052
  Materials are restricted until January 1, 2079 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
  - Correspondence, 1972-1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Judaic Studies program, 1981-1994 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - Koerner Center-Committee on Retirement, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Koerner Center for Emeritus Faculty dedication, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Penultimate Year evaluation, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Tasks and strategies for Religious Studies department, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Yale Chaplain search, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)